[Music]
Hello friends, I Manish Roda
from Investmart am going to discuss with you today a
comparison of some of the top health insurance plans in India. So
before starting the video, if you
are new to our channel then subscribe to our channel. Let's
start the comparison friends. Today we will
compare India's top three health
insurance plans
named ICICI Health Advantage
Plan, Star Health Assure Plan and Care
Supreme Plan. So let's discuss the comparison
of these plans. So let's start the
comparison friends. First of all, there are
some differences in the entry age of all the three health insurance plans. So let's
discuss the entry age. The
entry age in ICICI Health Advantage is 18 to 65
years. The entry age in Star Health Assure is
18 to 75 years. In Care Supreme, it is 18
to 60 years. In case of a dependent, it is 91
days to 25 years in ICICI.
In Star Assure, the dependent can live up to 17 years. The entry
age of the dependent in Care Supreme is  It ranges from 91 days to 24 years,
so this is the entry age. Now let's discuss
how much sum insured you can take in these policies.
In ICICI, the minimum sum insured is 5
lakhs, it can go up to 3 crores.
In Star Ayur, you can take a sum insured from 5 lakhs to 2 crores.
In Care Supreme, you
can take a sum insured from 5 lakhs to 1 crores.
Earlier, it used to be up to 15 lakhs. Recently, the
company has changed it and now you can take up
to 1 crore. So friends, now let's talk about
no claim bonus.
What is the benefit of no claim bonus in these policies? The
no claim bonus you get in ICICI
is up to
100%. 20% of every no claim year, you
get a no claim bonus. What does this mean?
Your no claim bonus in 5 years, combined with your
policy, gives you up to 100% no claim
bonus.  In the case of Star Assure,
you get up to 100%, but in that case,
you get a no-claim bonus of 25% every year. So, it
means that if your policy in Star Assure is of
10 lakhs, then it becomes 20 lakhs in 4 years, whereas
in the same ICICI, that
policy of 10 lakhs becomes 20 lakhs in 5 years.
And in the case of Care Supreme, you have
100% no-claim bonus, but in that, you
get a no-claim bonus of 50% every year. It means that the
policy of 10 lakhs becomes 20 lakhs in 2 years.
This is the benefit of no-claim bonus
in these three policies. So, friends,
now let us talk about the refill benefit,
what refill benefit you get in these policies.
In ICC,
you get a refill benefit once a year for any illness.
Your policy gets refilled up to the sum assured,
but for any illness and once a year
in Star Assure, you get 100% of sum assured.  You get
unlimited number of times for any illness
and in Care Supreme also you get
unlimited times refill benefit
and air ambulance is also available to you
friends in this in ICC it is covered up to sum assured
in Star Ashor it is covered up to 10 per
sum assured and in Care Supreme it is
covered up to 5 lakh only if you have taken a policy of
10 lakh or 20 lakh but it
gives you cover up to 5 lakh only
in Care Supreme friends now let us talk about
health checkup in these three policies
you get the benefit of health checkup
ICICI gives you % of sum assured and maximum up
to 10000 you health checkup benefit
it means if you have taken a policy of 10 lakh
then % of 10 lakh is 5000 you will
get health checkup benefit of 5000 to you and your
family and up to this maximum will be 10000
and at any sum assured cost same Star
Health  In Ashore, you get a
health checkup ranging from Rs. 1500 to Rs. 8000 in case of individual
and in case of floater you
get a health checkup ranging from Rs. 2500 to Rs. 15000 that depends
on sum assured only and
in case of Care Supreme you
can take health check benefit by taking an extra rider that is also
dependent on which
checkups will be covered in it that depends on your sum assured only
so you can take health checkup benefit in all the three cases friends
friends let's
talk about wellness benefit in this policy
ICICI does not provide you any wellness
benefit in this
Star Health Ashore provides wellness benefit up to 20
and Care Supreme
provides you wellness benefit up to 30.
E consultant is available in all these three policies,
you
can take your consultation from the doctor online, this
is covered in all the three policies apart from this
non payable item non payable  Items which are not
covered under some circumstances like your Dettol
sanitizers, PPE, etc. All these things
are covered in all three policies but there are
some conditions in them. In ICICI, you
can avail this rider called Claim
Protector. By purchasing that rider, your
non-payable items will be covered. In Star Health
Assure, it is inbuilt and automatic cover.
And in Care Supreme also, you
can cover these non-payable items by taking a rider. Friends, now let us talk about co-
payment and deductible.
What do co-payment and deductible mean? Some
people feel that the premium of their policy is a
bit high. By
reducing the premium in the same policy, you
can avail this benefit by making this co-payment or by applying deductible. ICICI Health
Advantage gives you the benefit of co-payment.
If you apply co-payment, the
premium of ICICI will be reduced and you
can take the policy. Same in the case of Star
Health Assure, you can avail the benefit of deductible.
Health Assurance
gives you the benefit of ₹50,000 deductible benefit, let us
also know its meaning,
friends, it means that if a
claim comes up to ₹50,00,000, then the company will
not give you even ₹1 in that, if any claim comes over
and above ₹50,000, you will get the claim, same
in the case of copayment and same in the case of
detachable, so IIC also gives you this benefit of
reducing the premium, Star
Assurance also gives you this benefit by
applying detachable, but Care Supreme
does not provide you this copayment and detachable benefit rider for reducing the premium,
so you
can take this thing according to your choice, friends, so now let us talk about
specified diseases, are
specified diseases covered in these policies,
friends, specified diseases in all three policies are
covered after 2 years
because these are the guidelines of IRDA
What are specified diseases? Specific
diseases like uterus removal, bone replacement,
cataract hernia, etc. are some of these diseases
which IIDA says that you should cover them after 2 years. So,
these specific diseases are covered in all three policies after two years.
Apart from this, after Pre-
Existify
[Music],
if you pay the premium for 1 year or 2 years, then
pre-existing diseases are covered after 3 years.
But if you pay the premium for 3 years
together, then
your pre-existing diseases are covered after 30 months.
Friends, and in Care Supreme,
pre-existing diseases are covered after 48 months, that is, after 4 years.
But if you
take a rider in it, then you can cover it till after one year.
Friends, it depends on whether
you paid the extra cost of the rider
and you can start your pre-existing disease early
coverage. So,
friends, now let us talk about maternity
expenses in ICICI.
Delivery expenses are covered by applying an extra rider.
You also get this coverage in Star Health Insurance,
which is available after 2 years.
If both husband and wife
are covered in the policy, then this coverage can be availed.
That is up to 10% of the sum assured. You
get this coverage and you do
not get delivery expenses coverage in Care Supreme.
Friends, now let us talk about
global coverage. In ICICI,
you get global coverage only in sums of up to 25 lakhs.
Global coverage is not available in Star Health Insurance.
You have this
global coverage covered in Care Supreme. Friends, now let us
talk about the most important thing, the claim settlement ratio.
Friends, normally when we
take a policy, we talk about the
claim ratio of the company.
This is a very big criteria while
choosing a policy. So, overall the
claim ratio of all three policies is very good. I will
tell you in numbers. The claim
settlement ratio of ICICI is 97.7 and that of Star Health
Insurance is 97.7.  It is 999.0 and the IT of Care Health is
100%, so all the claims that have come to E Care have been
settled by Care Health Insurance, so I am
not saying that Care is the best, ICICI is the
best and Star, all three are the best in their place because
now a claim settlement
ratio of 85 is considered good, friends, so you
can choose any of the three policies according to your choice,
friends, now we talk about day
care treatments, day care treatments are covered in all three policies,
what does day care treatment mean, those diseases which are covered due to
advancement of technology, single day without
24 hour hospitalization
or they are called day care treatment, they
are covered in all three, friends, if you have to
take domiciliary treatment either due to non-availability of the doctor
or the patient's
condition is such that he cannot go to the hospital, then
in both the cases, domiciliary hospitalization
is covered in all the three policies, friends, I have told you all the overall
features and comparison,
now I will tell you the basic USP  Let me talk about
what
extra benefit is there in all three, is there any USP
that you can consider while
taking the policy. Friends, now let us
talk about the USP of all three policies. The
maternity cover in ICICI Health Advantage starts after nine months.
If you take a rider for maternity coverage, then
you get the maternity
benefit after nine months. So this is a
very good USP of this. So those who
need maternity coverage can consider this and consider the
ICICI policy.
Friends, after that I will
talk about Star Health Ashor. The maximum
entry age in Star Health Ashor
is 75 years. The entry age
in the other two policies is 65
years. It gives the availability to a person up to 75 years of age to
enter the policy.
So this is its USP. Friends, there is
a very good benefit in Care Supreme
which is added with the rider. That is its super
no claim bonus.  What does it mean friends, firstly
you get a normal no claim bonus,
apart from that if you take this rider of
super no claim bonus then your no
claim bonus is 100% and
you get an extra benefit of Rs 500, this is a very
good benefit, let me tell you its meaning
in numbers that if you
take a policy of Rs 10 lakh then with normal no claim
bonus it will become of Rs 20 lakh, but if
you avail this super no claim bonus rider,
then you will
get an extra benefit of Rs 500, so that means the policy of Rs 10 lakh will become of Rs
70 lakh, friends, so this is a
very good benefit, you
can avail this in Care Supreme, so all these three
policies have their own USP, you
can opt for the policy according to your requirement and your choice, friends, so this was the
comparison of all the three policies, I have
discussed with you, now I will
also tell you the premium comparison of all the three policies at
a specific age, friends, now we will discuss the
premium  Let's talk about the
premium of all three policies.
In case of two adults plus two children, the age is 35 years. The
premium of IIC is
1952, the premium of Star Health Usher
is
2785 and the premium of Care is
17651. So these three premiums are the
premiums of Zone 3. Chandigarh comes in Zone 3,
so we have calculated these premiums for Chandigarh.
You can calculate your premium according to your age, the
link of which we have given
in the description box.
You will get the premium calculator, policy wording, everything in the description box,
friends. Apart from this, if you have any query,
our video is
always available, friends. Thank you,
friends. Next time, after this, we will bring a
new video.
Don't forget to like this video, don't forget to press the bell icon.
Thank you
[Music]
friends